《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
你现在还可以逃
You can still run.
找到小莱  好好生活
Find Lee, have a life.
我必须洗清我的罪名
I have to clear my name.
可是要怎么做
But how?
你已经正常了
You're sane.
继续关着你  不合法律也不道德
It would be unethical and illegal to keep you confined.
如果你总这么随随便便地放走疯子
If you keep releasing lunatics so liberally,
你会招来骂名的
you're going to get a bad reputation.
"火柴"马龙
Matches Malone.
我们见过吗
We've met before?
你杀了我父母
You killed my parents.
是谁雇了你
Who hired you?
你永远别想知道那人的名字
You'll never know their name.
布鲁斯
Bruce!
他在里面
He's in there.
你好  柯丽丝汀
Hello, Kristin.
你怎么会变成这样
How did you become this?
这才是我的本性
This is who I am.
所以嫁祸你才那么容易
That's what made it so easy to frame you!
放下枪
Drop the gun.
该死
Oh, crud.
那么  你什么时候回来工作
So... when are you coming back to work?
我答应布鲁斯·韦恩会解决他父母的案子
I promised Bruce Wayne I'd solve his parents' murder.
我得先做那个
I have to do that first.
韦恩案已经结了  吉姆
The Wayne case is closed, Jim.
犯人死了
The perp is dead.
但是谁雇了他  我得查明白
But who hired him? I need to find out.
早啊  维克多
Good morning, Victor.
我怎么还没死
How is it I'm not dead?
零点之上的温度会要你的命
Anything above freezing will kill you.
别担心  你不会永远被关在里面
But never fear, you won't be locked in there forever.
你知道卢修斯·福克斯先生修好了你爸的电脑
You do know that Mr. Lucius Fox fixed your old man's computer
但我不能让你把那姑娘也拉入危险中
but I will not have you put that little girl's life in danger.
要么做这个  要么选她
It's either the work, or it's her.
我不回去了
I'm not going back.
什么
What?
我该留在这儿
My place is here.
祝你人生愉快  布鲁斯·韦恩
Have a great life, Bruce Wayne.
你好  吉姆
Hi, Jim.
举起手来
Hands up. Hands up!
好  这样
Okay. Look.
可以了吗
Better?
进屋
Inside.
手举着  面朝墙
Keep them up. Face the wall.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
你不是在阿卡姆疯人院吗
You're supposed to be in Arkham.
你不是在黑门监狱吗
And you're supposed to be in Blackgate.
我洗清了我的罪名
I cleared my name.
我再问一遍  你来这里干什么
I'll ask you again. What are you doing here?
我被释放了
I was released.
打个电话你就知道了
Call them, you'll see.
我在说实话
I'm telling the truth.
我现在都说实话了
It's what I do now.
这很难相信
That's hard to believe.
哪一部分
Which part?
对天发誓  我今天真的很累
I swear to God, after the day I've had,
我毫不介意对你开枪
I have no problem shooting you.
听着  我相信你
Hey, look, I believe you.
听着  我从昏迷中醒来后
Look, when I came out of the coma,
我的记忆...令人恐惧
the memories I had were... horrifying.
像是从噩梦中惊醒
Like waking up from a nightmare.
做出那些事的人
The person who did those things,
那不是我
that's not me.
他们释放了你
So they released you.
就这样吗
Just like that.
也不是马上就放的
Well, not right away.
我显然有些问题要解决
I mean, I had some issues to work through, obviously.
但没错
But yes.
我好多了  吉姆
I'm better, Jim.
我神志正常
I'm totally sane.
真的
I really am.
我为你感到高兴
I'm happy for you.
请离开吧
Please, go.
你不相信我  是吗
You don't believe me, do you?
说实话  我不在乎
Frankly, I don't care.
就这样吗
What, and that's it?
我有工作要处理
I have work to do.
夫人
The Lady.
你在调查韦恩案  是吗
You're investigating the Wayne murder, huh?
我对她有所耳闻
I've heard of her.
你认为她有参与吗
You think she's involved?
我可以帮你
Cause I could help you with this.
不用  谢谢
No, thanks.
或许我来是个错误  但是听着
Okay, well, maybe it was a mistake to come, but listen.
你能再为我做一件事吗
Could you just do one more thing for me?
你能叫我的名字吗
Could you say my name?
再见  芭芭拉
Good-bye, Barbara.
你好  哈维
Hey, Harvey.
吉姆会和你解释的
Jim will catch you up.
吉姆...
Jim, um...
吉姆
Jim!
你都忙一整晚了  布鲁斯少爷
You've been at it all night, Master Bruce.
我觉得你应该吃点东西休息下
I think you should try and get some food down your neck.
那是香肠味儿吗
Do I smell sausage?
猪肉肠仔  福克斯先生
Chipolatas to you, Mr. Fox.
我在楼上准备了全套英式早餐
I've prepared a full English upstairs.
我不知道你说的是啥玩意
I have no idea if that's a yes,
但我饿死了
but I'm starving.
我们开吃吧
Let's eat.
我好像有发现
I think I found something.
你父亲的文件还在解码
Your father's files are still running through the decryption program.
得要几周才能知道里面有什么
It could take weeks before we know what we have.
没错  但这个日程表仅设了密码
Yes, but his calendar was only password protected.
密码是"布鲁斯"  和门锁一样
It was "Bruce," just like the lock.
与凯伦·詹妮斯见面
谈松林农场
看  这是他被杀的那周
Here-- the week of his murder,
他约好去见一个叫凯伦·詹宁斯的女人
he was supposed to meet a woman named Karen Jennings
谈关于"松林农场"的事
about something called "Pinewood Farms."
松林农场啊
Oh, Pinewood Farms.
听起来挺...古雅的
That sounds, uh, rather quaint.
也许并不
Or not.
韦恩集团大部分秘密项目
Most of Wayne Enterprises black op programs
都有那样的代号
had code names like that.
潺潺溪流  大风山脊
Running Brook. Windy Ridge.
用温文尔雅的名字掩饰肮脏的勾当
A bland name covering up nasty business.
这可能就是我父亲被杀时在调查的东西
This could be what my father was investigating when he was killed.
你是不是想多了
I think we might be getting a tad ahead of ourselves here,
布鲁斯少爷
Master Bruce.
假如这事就写在你老爹的
I mean, how covert could it possibly be
日程表上  这事能多秘密呢
if it's on your old man's calendar?
等我到公司  去人力资源部查查凯伦
I'll run Karen's name through HR when I get into work,
凯伦·詹妮斯
无电话
美国  哥谭市  梅尔伯恩街
看看有没有什么联系
see if there's even a connection.
我父亲有她的地址
My father had her address.
她就住在城外
She lives somewhere right outside the city.
我觉得我们该先等等
I think we should just wait
看看福克斯先生有什么发现  布鲁斯少爷
and see what Mr. Fox comes up with first, Master Bruce.
我不想等了  阿尔弗雷德
I'm done waiting, Alfred.
我要去找她  跟不跟我来随你
I'm going up there. With or without you.
我可真惊讶啊
Imagine my surprise.
你得在路上吃点东西
You are going to eat something on the way.
现在我们知道"火柴"马龙是受雇杀手
Now that we know Matches Malone was the triggerman,
我们可以往回追查
we can work backwards.
他的档案显示他主要为两个雇主办事
His file has him working primarily with two contractors--
一个已经死了
there's one's dead,
另一个被称为"夫人"
the other one's known as The Lady.
是她  派人去盖勒文顶层公寓杀你的
Her? She's the one that sent the assassins after you
就是她
at Galavan's penthouse.
是啊  就是她  你知道她在哪吗
Yeah. Her. You know where she's at?
消失了
In the wind.
你杀了她最好的人马后  她就歇业了
She went out of business after you killed her A team,
名声尽毁  很讽刺吧
put her rep in the toilet. Ironic, huh?
至少我有她熟人的名单
At least I have a list of her known associates.
暂时够用了
It'll have to do for now.
总有人知道她在哪里
Someone must know where she is.
听着  她的熟人都是职业杀手
Look, her known associates are professional hit men.
回哥谭市警局吧  这样你就有资源了
Come back to the GCPD, you'll have resources.
更别说  还有我
Not to mention, you know, me.
是啊  但巴恩斯也会死死盯着我
Yeah, and I'd have Barnes looking over my shoulder.
我得按我的方式来行事  至少目前是这样
I need to be able to do things my way, at least for now.
好吧  但别耽搁太久
All right, but don't take too much time, okay?
我还得负责训练阿尔瓦雷斯
I'm supposed to be training Alvarez.
简直像教大比目鱼穿袜子
It's like trying to teach a halibut how to put on socks.
就这样吗
Is that it?
你没有警徽了  搭档  记得吗
You don't carry a badge anymore, partner, remember?
我觉得你该从狠手抽屉里拿几样东西
I think you need to grab a few items from the whammy drawer.
他们居然放芭芭拉出了阿卡姆
Can you believe they let Barbara out of Arkham?
先是企鹅  然后是她
First Penguin, then her?
他们的大门不上锁了吗
What, they don't have locks on the doors?
选得好
Oh, good choice.
吉姆
Hey, Jim.
在外要小心
Be careful out there.
一向如此
Always.
哥谭的杀手今天要倒霉了
It's gonna be a bad day for the hit men of Gotham.
仅供学习  禁止商用  更多影视
登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 小胖纸Amy   辰星晓Reginamoon   Silence   DustD
翻译 charcie   大K   草草   后期 饿得慌
我问  夫人在哪
I said, where's The Lady?!
没人知道
No one knows!
时间轴 风吹来的那片云   校对&总监 草草
答错了
Wrong answer.
肯定有人知道
Someone knows.
我不知道  我发誓
I don't. I swear.
她在哪
Where is she?
她可能在阿耳特弥斯俱乐部
She might be at a club called Artemis.
谢谢
Thank you.
哥谭
第二季  第十八集
重要的时刻到来了  皮博迪女士
The moment has arrived, Ms. Peabody.
我们的成功或许终能让人类
Our success here could finally free humanity
摆脱死亡的枷锁
from the shackles of mortality.
我们开始尝试复苏后
As you said the first dozen times
这话你说过很多遍了  教授  但都失败了
we attempted reanimation, Professor-- and failed.
但是我对44号病人有很强烈的预感
Ah, but I have a very good feeling about Patient 44.
你该乐观一点
You need to be more positive.
韦恩集团有人搜索了凯伦·詹宁斯
Someone at Wayne Enterprises ran a search for Karen Jennings.
你觉得她被找到了吗
Do you think she's been found?
我认为不可能
I don't see how.
我们都一直没找到她  但有人在找她
We've never been able to, but someone is looking.
她是我们的第一个病人
She was our first.
千万可能性的起点
One small stroke on the canvas of possibilities.
那么有前途  记得吗
Such promise. Do you remember?
我记得她弄伤了一个看护人
I remember the orderlies she maimed
还杀了两个
and the two she killed.
创造总是如此暴力
Creation is always so violent.
松林
她可能会暴露我们
She could expose us.
哥谭市警局
刑事档案
凯伦  是谁在找你呢
Oh, Karen. Who's looking for you?
哥谭市警局
刑事档案
他们知道你变成了什么样吗
Do they know what you've become?
知道我把你变成了什么样吗
What I turned you into?
没人在家
Nope.
不走运  没关系
No joy. Never mind.
离开庄园  在乡间开车兜风
Still kind of nice to get out of the manor,
还是挺开心的
have a little drive in the country.
真不错
Ah, that's terrific, isn't it?
她把你教成小贼了
She's made a bloody tea leaf out of you.
街头生存技能吗  才怪
Street smarts? Street smarts, my eye.
别说话  阿尔弗雷德
Shush, Alfred.
这只是些技能而已
These are merely technical skills.
道德中立
Morally neutral.
怎么了
What is it?
小心  布鲁斯少爷
Careful, Master Bruce.
她拿着什么奇怪的狩猎刀
She's got some kind of weird hunting knife.
我们不想伤害你
We don't want to hurt you.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
抬起枪  抬起枪
Raise the gun. Raise the gun.
我叫布鲁斯·韦恩
My name is Bruce Wayne.
我只想和你谈谈
I just want to talk to you.
布鲁斯·韦恩
Bruce Wayne?
你就是布鲁斯·韦恩
You're Bruce Wayne?
别再靠近了
That's far enough.
放下刀
Drop the knife.
那不是把刀
It's not a knife.
不管你用什么把我伤成这样
Whatever it was you used to do this to me,
给我扔掉  马上
just drop it. Right now.
我做不到
I can't.
听我说
Listen to me...
-别再靠近了  -阿尔弗雷德
- That's far enough. - Alfred!
看看周围  布鲁斯少爷
Well, look around you, Master Bruce.
听着  我不知道
Listen, I've no idea
你是什么东西  但不管那玩意是什么
what you are, but whatever that thing is...
它非常危险
it's bloody dangerous.
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
你似乎认得我
You seemed to recognize me.
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
我父亲  托马斯·韦恩
My father, Thomas Wayne,
死前一周曾来过这里
came here the week before he died.
他写在日程表里了
He had it in his calendar.
他的日程表  太好了
His calendar? Great.
你被跟踪了吗
Were you followed?
没有
No.
我不知道  被谁跟踪
I-I-I don't know. By who?
没  我们...
No. No, we...
我们没被跟踪
we weren't followed.
太好了
Good.
那你们可以走了
Then you can leave.
你得先回答我的问题
Not until you answer my questions.
我知道我父亲是来找你谈
I know my father came to talk to you
松林农场的事  那是什么
about something called Pinewood Farms. What is that?
天啊  你什么也不知道  是不是
God, you don't know anything, do you?
那就告诉我
So tell me.
你明不明白  那些人会杀了你的
Do you not understand that these people will kill you?
你以为我没跟他说过这些吗
Don't you think I've been trying to tell him that?
我不怕死
I'm not afraid to die.
如果是为了正义事业的话
Not if it means doing the right thing.
是吗
Yeah?
看看你爸是什么下场吧
How'd that work out for your dad?
你得走了
You have to go.
你在这里不安全
It's not safe for you here.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我父亲所调查的事
Whatever my father was investigating
导致他和我妈被杀
got him and my mom killed.
你是我找到第一个也许知道原因的人
You're the first person I've found who might know why.
求你
Please.
你必须告诉我他在做什么
You have to tell me what he was doing.
阿耳特弥斯是私人俱乐部  先生
The Artemis is a private club, sir.
我得进去找个人
I need to see if someone's inside.
很快就好
It'll just take a minute.
只接待会员
Members only.
吉姆
Jim.
真巧啊
What a coincidence.
能跟他说句话吗
Can I borrow him a moment?
我昨晚说得不清楚吗
Did I not make myself clear last night?
很清楚
Oh, you did.
我也想尊重你的界限
And I wanted to respect your boundaries.
但不知你是否了解
But I was wondering if you knew
这个俱乐部只限女性
that this is a women's only club.
而且可以说  里面的会员都有罪犯倾向
Plus, its members are, shall we say, of a criminal persuasion.
我就知道
Didn't think so.
所以我来了
Which is why I'm here.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你要替我跟夫人谈
You're gonna talk to The Lady for me,
获取我要的信息
get the information I need,
只要我...相信你吗
if I just... what? Trust you?
没人喜欢自作聪明的人
No one likes a smarty-pants.
那你有何计划
So what's your plan, then?
我的计划吗
My plan?
我的计划是拿枪对准夫人的脸
My plan is to stick a gun in The Lady's face
让她求我不要开枪
and have her beg me not to pull the trigger
直到她说出我想知道的一切
until she tells me everything I want to know.
戈登特色
The Gordon special.
历历在目啊
I remember it well.
问题是
Problem is,
你现在不是警察了
you're not a cop anymore.
话说  这是为什么呢
Why is that, by the way?
重点是  如果你进去持枪相向
The point is, if you go in there guns blazing,
夫人会消失  可能就此无影无踪
The Lady will disappear, probably for good.
我可以进去得到你要的东西
I can go inside and get you what you want.
有什么不好呢
What do you have to lose?
你为什么这么做
Why are you doing this?
我当时在场
I was there.
记得吗
Remember?
你最初接手韦恩案时
When you first caught the Wayne case.
我知道这对你意味着什么
I know what it means to you.
你觉得如果能了结此案
You think that if you can solve it,
就能关上通往过去的门
you can close the door on the past.
或许  只是或许
And maybe, just maybe,
这扇门就将再不开启
it'll stay shut.
那样你就能重新开始
And then you'll be able to start over.
你真要问  我为什么这么做吗
And you really have to ask me why I'm doing this?
给妹子买杯喝的
Buy a girl a drink?
我们见过吗
Have we met?
没
No.
但我挺出名的
But I'm kind of famous.
臭名昭著的芭芭拉·基恩
The notorious Barbara Kean.
请坐
Please...
抱歉伤了你的手
Sorry about your hand.
我这儿不常有人来
I don't get many visitors.
你们...吓着我了
You, uh, spooked me.
慢着  什么  我们吓到你了
Wait, what, we-we-we spooked you?
你在这里住了多久
How long have you lived here?
十年
Ten years.
从松林出来后就住这儿
Ever since Pinewood.
你是在那里
Is that where you...
被改造成这样吗
got that?
松林农场是韦恩集团旗下的
Pinewood Farms was a bioengineering program
生物工程项目
at Wayne Enterprises.
是个秘密项目
The kind that was kept off the books.
我是他们招募的第一批志愿者
I was one of their first volunteers.
什么  你主动去改造吗
What, you volunteered for that, did you?
我当时没得选
I didn't have many options at the time.
我当时在黑门监狱
I was at Blackgate.
黑门监狱
Blackgate.
"真好"
Nice.
你不是在那里做狱警的吧
Take it you weren't a guard, then.
我的胳膊先天残疾
I was born with a crippled arm.
从小到大  我父亲喜欢做两件事
Growing up, my father liked two things:
酗酒  打自己的残疾女儿
booze and beating his deformed daughter.
有一天晚上  我还手了
One night, I fought back.
他摔下楼梯
He fell down the stairs
摔断了脖子
and broke his neck.
我因杀人罪去黑门监狱坐牢
I went to Blackgate for murder.
但那是正当防卫
But that's self-defense.
人们畏惧与众不同的人
Well, people are scared of different.
陪审团判我有罪
Jury sent me away.
一天  一些人找到我
One day, these men show up.
说他们能治好我的胳膊
Tell me they're gonna fix my arm.
不仅能治好  还会让它变得更棒
Not only fix it, make it better.
相反  他们把我变成了人们心目中的怪物
Instead, they turned me into the monster everybody thought I was.
我父亲知道松林农场的事吗
Did my father know what was going on at Pinewood Farms?
不  不知道
No. No.
他发现后
When he found out what was going on,
他得知对我们进行的实验后
when he saw what they were doing to us,
他叫停了项目
he shut it down.
花钱让我们躲起来
Paid to put us into hiding.
一共有多少你这样的人
So how many were there of you?
不清楚
Not sure.
我知道大部分都没在实验中活下来
I know most didn't survive the experiments.
这个项目又开始运行了吧
It started up again, didn't it?
所以我父亲才在那么多年后又来见你
That's why my father came to see you after all those years.
他不确定  但
He wasn't sure, but...
他有所怀疑
he had his suspicions.
他过来提醒我
He came to warn me.
松林农场的负责人
Whoever was running Pinewood,
重启了项目的人
whoever started it up again,
就是杀死我父母的人
I know that's who killed my parents.
你记得他们的名字吗
Do you remember any names?
他们都不在我们面前称呼名字
None of them ever used their names around us.
但是那个负责人
But the man who was in charge...
他的样子我仍然历历在目
I can still see his face.
每次我闭上眼睛时都能看见
Every time I close my eyes.
你得带我们过去
Then you need to take us there.
你得带我们去松林农场
You need to take us to Pinewood Farms.
我父亲为救你冒了生命危险
My father risked his life to save you.
我求你还他这个情
I'm asking you to repay that favor.
我保证
I promise...
你不会有事的
...nothing will happen to you.
好吧
Okay.
是啊
Yeah.
的确不尽如人意  但无所谓了
It didn't go quite to plan, but whatever.
我穿那身婚纱可美了
I looked incredible in that wedding dress.
我猜也是
I suspect you did.
你怎么从阿卡姆出来的
And how did you get out of Arkham?
很简单
Well, that was easy.
就是各种...
It was a lot of...
"天呐
"Oh, my God.
我居然杀了那么多人"
I can't believe I killed all those... people."
你现在打算怎么办
Well, what's your plan now?
这个嘛
Well...
我在考虑进入刺杀这行
I'm thinking about getting into the assassination business.
但我需要个搭档
Only I need a partner.
你有什么筹码
What do you have to offer?
我有钱  漂亮
I'm rich, fabulous,
而且就你而言  我正好有
and, in your case, I may have just the thing
能恢复你名誉的办法
to restore your reputation.
是吗
Really?
好了  下周再见
All right, see you next week!
我帮帮你吧
Let me help you with that!
多谢
Thanks.
挺固执啊
Stubborn.
我需要见夫人
I need to speak to The Lady.
她在等你
She's expecting you.
吉姆
Hey, Jim.
你猜怎么着
Guess what?
你都说对了
You were right.
有没有人觉得特别似曾相识
Is anyone getting major déjà vu, here?
等等
Only, wait...
还差小莱
We're missing Lee.
可惜
Shame.
否则这个家庭团聚得多好玩
That would've been a real family reunion.
你就是为了这个
So that's what this has been about?
把我交给她
Delivering me to her?
我在你文件里看到了她的照片
Well, when I saw her picture in your file,
就猜到你要追查她  于是自己查了查
I figured you'd go after her, so I did some digging.
发现你俩有点渊源
Saw you two had some history
一切就水到渠成了
and it all kind of... came together.
我是不是做到了
So did I deliver or what?
你说他在找我时
When you said he was looking for me,
我还以为这是为了
I assumed this had something to do
我派去杀他的人
with the men I sent to kill him.
不
No.
他知道你安排"火柴"马龙
He knows you contracted Matches Malone
去杀韦恩夫妇
for the Wayne murders,
而他一心想查明
and he is just obsessed with finding out
是谁雇了你
who hired you.
这是他的执迷
It's like his thing.
他是为这个来的
That's why he's here?
我完全不知道是谁指使了韦恩的刺杀
I have absolutely no idea who's behind the Wayne murders.
你没接合同吗
You didn't take the contract?
没  我是接了
Oh, no. I mean, I did, but...
但一切都是在电话里谈妥的
we did it all over the telephone.
我没见过客户
I never met the client.
但你肯定知道个名字啊
But you must've got a name.
他一直以外号自居
He went by a nickname.
可怜的吉姆
Poor Jim.
这么接近了
So close.
真是可惜你得死了
It's almost sad you have to die.
我们告诉他吧
You know, should we just tell him?
你总这么感性吗
Are you always this sentimental?
好吧
Fine.
他自称
He called himself
"哲学家"
The Philosopher.
好了  吉姆
There you go, Jim.
这下你知道了
Now you know.
告诉你我自有计划了
Told you I had a plan.
这可不像什么
That doesn't exactly scream
"绝密生物工程实验室"  是吧
"top secret bioengineering lab," does it?
就是这里
This is it.
好吧  你俩坐好
Right. You two sit tight.
我就回来
I'll have a shifty.
真是的
Honestly.
她来了
She's here.
好
Right.
我敢说都十年没人来过了
I'd wager nothing's been touched in here for a decade.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
看到这一切
Seeing all this,
让发生的一切又恍如昨日
it feels like yesterday that I was here.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
看来你父亲错了
Uh, looks like your father was wrong.
或许这也好
Maybe it's for the best.
你可以向前看了
You can move on now.
你知道这里被关闭了  是吧
You knew this place was shut down, didn't you?
所以你才带我来吗  希望我会放弃
Is that why you brought me here, hoping I'd give up?
别激动  布鲁斯少爷
Steady on, Master Bruce.
不  她有所隐瞒
No, she's hiding something.
我能从她的眼神中看出来
I can see it in her eyes.
我不懂  你究竟瞒着我什么
I don't understand. What won't you tell me?
这里是私人领地
This is private property!
我要报警了
I'm gonna call the cops!
姑娘跟我们走就不会有人受伤
Girl comes with us, and no one gets hurt.
快跑  布鲁斯少爷
Run, Master Bruce.
快跑
Run!
走吧
Come on.
放下枪  马上
Drop the gun, now!
你走那边  我去这边找
You go down... and I'll look this way.
好
Got it.
那是怎么回事
What the hell was that about?
别生气
Don't be mad.
我被绑在了椅子上  又一次差点被杀
I was tied to a chair and nearly killed. Again.
我该有什么感觉
What should I be feeling?
感激
Gratitude?
我没那个感觉
I'm not feeling that.
我需要夫人信任我
I needed The Lady to trust me.
这叫计划
It's called a plan.
计划
A plan?
如果我没进去呢
What if I'd stayed outside?
得了吧
Really?
瞧  我们知道名字了
Look, we got the name.
我们应该庆祝才是
We should be celebrating.
我们挺默契的
We kind of make a pretty good team.
这并不能改变什么
This doesn't change anything.
我如约帮你套到了信息
I got you the information that I said I would.
我做的一切都是为了你
Everything I did in there, I did for you.
你肯定明白吧
You have to see that.
老实说  我不知道我看到了什么
Honestly, I don't know what I see.
那就看啊
Then look.
求你
Please.
你为什么在乎
What do you care?
发生了那么多事
After everything that's happened,
就算你变了
let's say you've changed.
你在乎我的想法干什么
What do you care what I think?
因为我从昏迷中醒来时
Because when I woke up from that coma,
脑子里最先浮现的就是你的脸
the first image I saw was your face
是你在教堂窗口抓住我的样子
as you were holding on to me from the church window.
你是想救我
You were trying to save me.
因为在那一刻  你看到的不是魔鬼
Because in that moment, you didn't see the monster.
而是我
You just saw me.
这是我的支撑
That's what I've been holding on to.
因为我觉得
Because I feel like
如果你能再次那么看我
if you could just look at me like that again...
我就会没事了
I'd be okay.
我就能撑下来
I'd make it.
你想做个更好的人
You want to be a better person?
是的
Yes.
那是你的选择
That's your choice to make.
但我不能帮你
I can't be that for you.
你企图杀小莱
You tried to kill Lee.
这我不能原谅
I can't forgive that.
我不会原谅
I won't.
布鲁斯
来电
接吧
Just get it.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
慢点说
Slow down, slow...
Slow...
我就去
Be right there.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred!
早该放我了  伙计
About bloody time, mate.
我没法决定  伙计
Not my call, pal.
你别老被捕了好不好
How about you stop getting arrested so much?
布鲁斯呢
Where's Bruce?
在巴恩斯那儿
In with Barnes.
布洛克
Bullock!
准备转移凯伦·詹妮斯
Prep Karen Jennings to travel.
今天就送她去黑门监狱
I want her at Blackgate today.
不得接触
No contact.
你可以走了
You, you're free to go.
我改主意之前你最好赶紧走
I suggest you do so before I change my mind.
你跟他说了什么
What did you tell him?
实话
The truth.
他似乎不太高兴
He didn't seem to like it.
好吧  你跟我说说
All right, how about you tell me?
你父亲得知了这个项目
So your father found out about this program,
而凯伦·詹妮斯是个实验对象
where Karen Jennings was a subject,
之后他就关闭了项目
and shut it down.
项目重启后
When it was restarted,
他企图阻止
he tried to stop it...
他们就杀了他
and they had him killed.
你觉得凯伦能辨认出涉案的人
And you think Karen can identify the men involved?
不知道他们的名字
Doesn't know their names.
但她说能记得那些人的样子
Says she can remember their faces, though.
雇"火柴"马龙杀你父母的人
The man who contracted Matches Malone to kill your parents
自称"哲学家"
called himself The Philosopher.
等等
Hold on,
你怎么知道的
how'd-how'd you know this?
我自己也在进行调查
I've been conducting my own investigation.
我今天才得知的
I found out today.
我敢打赌  此人就是
And I'd be willing to bet that this is the man
松林幕后的黑手
who was behind Pinewood.
我们怎么办
What do we do?
让卢修斯·福克斯整理
Have Lucius Fox put together the files
这15年来所有为韦恩集团工作的
of all the scientists who have worked for Wayne Enterprises
科学家的档案
over the past 15 years.
如果凯伦能把此人认出来
If Karen can pick this man out,
如果他就是哲学家
if he is The Philosopher,
我们就可以证明他与你父母之死有关
we can tie him to your parents' murder.
当然  这得是凯伦·詹宁斯还活着
Assuming, of course, that Karen Jennings is still alive.
这些人显然不是闹着玩的
I mean, it's obvious these guys mean business.
她一进黑门监狱就必死无疑
She's gonna be dead the minute she hits Blackgate Prison.
所以我们得去劫囚
That's why we're gonna break her out.
你短时间内能凑到多少钱
How much money can you put together quickly?
你需要多少
How much do you need?
44号病人的脑电图表明了反常睡眠
Patient 44's EEG patterns confirm paradoxical sleep.
我们接近了
We're getting close.
他也接近了
He's... getting close.
凯伦·詹宁斯被捕了
Karen Jennings was arrested
正在被送往黑门监狱
and is being sent to Blackgate Prison.
可惜啊
Pity.
看来我们不能再想着把她弄回来了
Seems we should abandon our efforts to bring her back.
她绝不能开口
She cannot be allowed to talk.
我派人过去
I'll send a team.
其实  我在考虑
Actually, I was thinking
这正是让我们的
this would be the perfect opportunity
零下男试试新装的绝佳机会
to let our sub-zero guest try out his new suit.
你确定
You sure?
不管那气体对他做了什么
Whatever that gas did to him,
他已经不是过去那个他了
he's not the man he was before.
他似乎  很愤怒
He seems... very angry.
我知道
I know.
我正在听呢
I was listening to that.
你好  维克多
Hello, Victor.
你感觉如何
How are you feeling?
我感觉如何
How am I feeling?
我被关在大冰柜里  你觉得呢
I'm locked in a freezer-- how do you think I'm feeling?
我就是为此而来
That's why I'm here.
你想不想
How would you like to go on a little...
出去走一趟
field trip?
搞什么
What the hell?
我去
Damn.
马蒂
Yo, Marty!
你绝不会相信的
You're never gonna believe it.
你自己决定
You have a decision to make!
留下钱  丢下枪
You can keep the money, toss us your gun
告诉你的上司你被制服了
and tell your supervisor you were disarmed,
要么就逞英雄
or be a hero,
像你朋友一样醒来
and wake up like your friend here
除了头疼什么都没有
with nothing to show for it but a massive headache.
我觉得这很好决定  你说呢
I'd say it's a bit of a no-brainer, wouldn't you, sweetheart?
枪给我
Give me your gun.
真乖
Good girl.
走吧
Go ahead.
钱留着享用吧
Enjoy your cash.
我们走
Let's go!
布鲁斯  怎么回事  这是谁
Bruce, what is going on? Who is this?
-一个朋友  -认识你很高兴
- A friend. - Nice to meet you.
他会帮我们送你出城
He's gonna help us get you out of town.
我准备了车
I have a car,
现金和新身份
cash and a new identity
都在韦恩庄园等着你
waiting for you back at Wayne Manor.
你居然会这么帮我
I can't believe you would do this for me.
我保证过不会让你出事
I made a promise nothing would happen to you.
我不会食言的
I intend to keep it.
凯伦
Karen?
你认识一个自称"哲学家"的人吗
Do you know a man who goes by the nickname The Philosopher?
那就是管理项目的人
That's, uh, the man who ran the program.
其他人都这么喊他
That's what the others called him.
似乎是他们的一个什么游戏
Something about some game they played.
你能辨认他吗
And you could identify him?
-能  -太好了
- Yeah. - Good.
我们有人在整理这些年来所有
We have someone tracking down the files of all the scientists
为韦恩集团工作过的科学家的档案
who have worked for Wayne Enterprises over the years.
之后你就可以消失了
After that, you, you can disappear.
再不会有人伤害你了
No one will ever hurt you again.
你口气跟他一样
You sound just like him.
我是有事隐瞒你  布鲁斯
I have been hiding something from you, Bruce.
我父亲并不仅仅把我救出了松林农场
Your father did more than just rescue me from Pinewood.
什么意思
What, what do you, what do you mean?
那事之后  我好愤怒
After what happened, I was so angry.
但他一直没放弃我
But he never gave up on me.
他经常来看我
He kept visiting.
送我书让我看
Gave me books to read.
生日时还送了我音乐盒
A music box for my birthday.
他一直提醒我  我不是一个人
He kept reminding me that I wasn't alone.
我不是个怪物
That I wasn't a monster.
我一直不知道真正的父亲该是个什么样
I never knew what a real father should be
直到我遇见托马斯·韦恩
until Thomas Wayne.
所以我才不希望你追查此事
That's why I didn't want you to pursue this.
我不希望你对他有不好的看法
I didn't want you to see him differently.
你父亲创建了松林农场  布鲁斯
Your father started Pinewood, Bruce.
他的意图是好的
His intentions were good.
但负责人利用了他
But the man in charge took advantage of him.
直到为时已晚他才发现真相
He didn't realize the truth until it was too late.
松林农场是他的负担
Pinewood was his burden.
但不非得成为你的
But it doesn't have to be yours.
这不是负担
It's not a burden.
是我的为人
It's who I am.
坐稳
Hold on!
维克多
Victor?
是你
You.
放下枪
Put down the gun!
带布鲁斯走
Go get on Bruce!
你们都没事吧
You both all right?
你没事
You all right?
快走
Go.
跑吧  他要的是我
Go, run. It's me he's after.
我们不会丢下你的
We're not leaving without you.
我很高兴能认识你  布鲁斯
I'm so glad I met you, Bruce.
你爸爸会很为你骄傲的
Your dad would be proud of you.
为你的成长自豪
Of the man that you've become.
-凯伦  凯伦  -别过去
- Karen! Karen... - Stay here!
-不  凯伦  凯伦  -退后
- No! Karen! Karen! - Get back.
抱歉  我来迟了
Sorry, I'm late.
我买到了你喜欢的盐水太妃糖
I did get you that salt water taffy you like, so...
你要吵醒她的
You'll wake her.
我以为她在阿卡姆
I thought she was in Arkham.
处于昏迷之中
In a coma.
现在不是了
Not anymore.
她几小时前跑来的
She showed up a couple of hours ago.
小可怜
Poor thing.
她来这儿做什么
What is she doing here?
她回家了
She's come home.
我父亲冒生命危险保护她
My father risked his life to protect her.
他在乎她
He cared for her.
现在她死了
And now she's dead.
就因为我
Because of me.
致凯伦  生日快乐  托马斯
不是因为你  布鲁斯少爷
Not because of you, Master Bruce.
是因为你的追寻
Because of what you're pursuing.
有什么区别吗
Is there a difference?
有
Yes.
如果你不能安心
And if you can't make your peace with that,
那你就还没准备好
then you're not ready.
还会有其他人  布鲁斯少爷
There will be others, Master Bruce.
凯伦是唯一知道
Karen was the only one who knew
哲学家长什么样的人
what The Philosopher looked like.
我们这下要怎么找他
How are we going to find him now?
你得有信心  布鲁斯
You need to have faith, Bruce.
我知道你今天冒了多大险
I know what you risked today.
如果巴恩斯查明你与此事有关
If Barnes finds out you were involved...
他会发现的
He will.
或许他已经发现了
If he hasn't already.
我在哥谭市警局应该是混不下去了
Pretty sure my days at the GCPD are over.
但我早就做好了这个准备
But I knew that going in.
那你为什么那么做
Then why'd you do it?
你不是唯一许下承诺的人
You're not the only one who made a promise.
福克斯先生
Ah, Mr. Fox.
我自己进来的
I let myself in.
我可能有发现
I think I might have something.
我整理科学家人事档案的时候
When I was compiling the personnel files on scientists,
我还进行了对比搜索
I also ran a cross-reference search
松林农场和哲学家
on Pinewood Farms and The Philosopher
发现了这个
and found this.
是12年前的一张公司时讯
It's from a company newsletter taken 12 years ago.
照片里有团队外号
The photo lists team nicknames.
看看你父亲身边的那个人
Look at the man next to your father.
雨果·斯特兰奇  "哲学家"
雨果·斯特兰奇
Hugo Strange.
哲学家
The Philosopher.
他现在是阿卡姆的主管
He runs Arkham now.
是朋友
A friend.
是他信任的人
Someone he... he trusted.
这不公平
That's not fair.
这不对
That's not right.
凯伦  真是可惜
Oh, Karen. What a shame.
你是那么有前途
You held such promise.
维克多说他认出了吉姆·戈登
Victor said he recognized Jim Gordon.
说他身边还有个孩子
Said he was with a boy.
布鲁斯·韦恩
Bruce Wayne.
那么他和吉姆·戈登在联手合作
So he and Jim Gordon are working together.
好啊
Well, well.
我觉得我们的生活
I think life is about to get
要变得很有趣了  皮博迪女士
very interesting for us, Ms. Peabody.
楼下的
It's coming from downstairs.
44号病人
Patient 44.
但复苏还有12小时的进程啊
But the reanimation should take another 12 hours.
-我...  -抓住他
- I... - Grab him, grab him!
皮博迪  我们做到了
Oh, Peabody, we did it.
我们复活了一个人
We brought someone back.
我们真做到了
We actually did it.
怎么了  妹妹
Wh... What is it now, sister?
他说什么
What's he saying?
异教恶犬
Heathen dogs.
又怎么了  妹妹
What now, sister?
圣城啊
The Holy City.
我知道了
Oh, I see.
圣徒会拯救我们
The saint will deliver us.
不  别走
No, don't leave.
别走
Don't leave.
要我放麻醉气吗
Should I gas him?
死亡天使阿泽瑞尔
Azrael...
死亡天使
Azrael!
Azrael.